# **Andrew S**

SF Bay Area, CA | linkedin.com/in/andrew-sons

# Quality Assurance ■ Program Management ■ Software Development

Self-motivated and accomplished Quality Assurance and Software Development specialist with 13+ years of industry experience. Highly skilled in programming, developing test plans and automation tools. Extensive experience with programming languages such as JavaScript, React, React Native, JQuery, HTML, CSS, Java, C++/#, Python, Ruby, with proficiency in Agile, Scrum and Waterfall methodologies. Enterprising strategist and empowering leader who exhibits ethical stewardship and a commitment to excel.

# **Skills**

JavaScript | React | React Native | JQuery | HTML | CSS | Java | C++/# | Python | Ruby | Photoshop | Illustrator | Excel | JIRA | Scrum & Waterfall | Team Building | Project Management

# Experience

## **HULU LLC** | Novato, CA

4/2017-10/2018

#### **QA Automation Engineer Lead**

- Crafted tools for installing our application on smart TVs, different brands used different methods; tools were user friendly and GUI based resulting in accelerated company wide adoption.
- Managed an internal team testing across multiple platforms (streaming boxes, smart TVs, video game consoles).
- Wrote and maintained automation and test applications in Python and JavaScript/Mocha.
- Oversaw the creation and distribution of builds to distinct platforms, compiled reports and Sprint forecasts
- Created and executed test plans and test cases, analyzed results, reported and tracked defects, verified fixes, and performed follow-up work to resolve issues.
- Launched a reporting and forecasting system to better assess the workload for each sprint leading to more accurate and informed expectations of how much work could be completed for each sprint.

## **LEAPFROG ENTERPRISES Inc. | Emeryville, CA**

#### Firmware QA Engineer Lead

4/2014-4/2017

- Led an internal and external team and maintained developer relations through the app development process from ideation to creation.
- Collaborated cross-functionally to do UX research, implement localization, and create game design proposals.
- Authored and maintained automation and test applications in C++, Java, Ruby, and Python.
- Conducted White and Black box testing on Android, Linux, and proprietary platforms.
- Spearheaded the collaboration for the Android tablet development between two offsite teams; China built the firmware and Canada built the UI. Acted as the go between the two development teams to explain expectations and project roles.
- Due to China's team being faster the firmware was ready for preliminary testing before the UI. I wrote a stand in application in Java to take the place of the UI. The application made the calls to the firmware that needed to be tested resulting in the application adoption into the automation suite.
- Established priorities, addressed all technical issues and led the successful project completion.

#### ZYNGA | San Francisco, CA

8/2009-5/2013

**Assistant Producer** 

5/2012-5/2013

- Managed the timely flow of projects, design/development/QA schedules, budgets, and deliverable milestones.
- Assisted in the creation of game features and art assets. Organized and launched advertisement campaigns/promotions with external vendors, including Honda, McDonald's, and Discover Card

#### **Quality Assurance Lead/Release Manager**

8/2009-5/2012

- Developed test plans and conducted testing on both browser-based and mobile games.
- Managed daily releases using Jira and Hudson; worked closely with engineers, artists, and project managers to improve testing/releasing strategies and ensure the timely release of features.

## **Education**